<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Widgets on Experiences of a developer</title>
    <link>bleathem.github.io/bleathem.ca/tags/widgets/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Widgets on Experiences of a developer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="bleathem.github.io/bleathem.ca/tags/widgets/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Spoke on Polyglot Widgets at JAXConf 2013</title>
      <link>bleathem.github.io/bleathem.ca/blog/spoke-on-polyglot-widgets-at-jaxconf-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>bleathem.github.io/bleathem.ca/blog/spoke-on-polyglot-widgets-at-jaxconf-2013/</guid>
      <description>This week I attended the JAXConf 2013 conference for a third year in a row. This year JAXConf was held in Santa Clara, the heart of silicon valley. The conference once again had a fantastic line up of speakers, with well recognized industry leaders speaking on a variety of current and exciting topics. Unfortunately, JAX continued this year to be one of the best kept secrets of the tech industry on the West coast, with attendance not being as strong as many would have liked.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking on Polyglot Widgets at JAXConf 2013</title>
      <link>bleathem.github.io/bleathem.ca/blog/speaking-on-polyglot-widgets-at-jaxconf-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>bleathem.github.io/bleathem.ca/blog/speaking-on-polyglot-widgets-at-jaxconf-2013/</guid>
      <description>JAXConf 2013   I will be returning to speak at JAXConf again this year. I&amp;rsquo;ll be speaking on the topic of Poly-framework Web applications with Java EE. The session will further explore the ideas I presented in my Polyglot Widgets blog, where I demoed a sample application written using three different web frameworks, demonstrating both a consistent look &amp;amp; feel, and uniform server-side programming model.
This topic will be particularly useful for those JAX attendees that have existing applications in production, yet like what they see with new web technologies and frameworks that they will learn about while attending JAXConf.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Polyglot Widgets</title>
      <link>bleathem.github.io/bleathem.ca/blog/polyglot-widgets/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>bleathem.github.io/bleathem.ca/blog/polyglot-widgets/</guid>
      <description>JBoss Developer Framework   The JBoss JDF project shows Java EE developers how to build state-of-the-art applications using the JBoss implementations of the Java EE stack. Specifically, the JDF View Frameworks section identifies a number of alternative approaches one can take when developing the view layer of your application. We in the RichFaces project have been working towards better supporting this effort by redesigning our JSF component architecture to allow the javascript part of our components (what we call our &amp;ldquo;widgets&amp;rdquo;) to be used independent of JSF, either in a standalone manner or coupled with another web framework.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>