<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>JAXConf on Experiences of a developer</title>
    <link>bleathem.github.io/bleathem.ca/tags/jaxconf/</link>
    <description>Recent content in JAXConf on Experiences of a developer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="bleathem.github.io/bleathem.ca/tags/jaxconf/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Spoke on Polyglot Widgets at JAXConf 2013</title>
      <link>bleathem.github.io/bleathem.ca/blog/spoke-on-polyglot-widgets-at-jaxconf-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>bleathem.github.io/bleathem.ca/blog/spoke-on-polyglot-widgets-at-jaxconf-2013/</guid>
      <description>This week I attended the JAXConf 2013 conference for a third year in a row. This year JAXConf was held in Santa Clara, the heart of silicon valley. The conference once again had a fantastic line up of speakers, with well recognized industry leaders speaking on a variety of current and exciting topics. Unfortunately, JAX continued this year to be one of the best kept secrets of the tech industry on the West coast, with attendance not being as strong as many would have liked.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking on Polyglot Widgets at JAXConf 2013</title>
      <link>bleathem.github.io/bleathem.ca/blog/speaking-on-polyglot-widgets-at-jaxconf-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>bleathem.github.io/bleathem.ca/blog/speaking-on-polyglot-widgets-at-jaxconf-2013/</guid>
      <description>JAXConf 2013   I will be returning to speak at JAXConf again this year. I&amp;rsquo;ll be speaking on the topic of Poly-framework Web applications with Java EE. The session will further explore the ideas I presented in my Polyglot Widgets blog, where I demoed a sample application written using three different web frameworks, demonstrating both a consistent look &amp;amp; feel, and uniform server-side programming model.
This topic will be particularly useful for those JAX attendees that have existing applications in production, yet like what they see with new web technologies and frameworks that they will learn about while attending JAXConf.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JAXConf-2012: JSF - Components &amp; Mobile</title>
      <link>bleathem.github.io/bleathem.ca/blog/jaxconf-2012-jsf---components--mobile/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>bleathem.github.io/bleathem.ca/blog/jaxconf-2012-jsf---components--mobile/</guid>
      <description>JAX Conf 2012   RichFaces represented at the &amp;ldquo;2012 JAX conference&amp;rdquo;:http://jaxconf.com/2012/ in San Francisco this week. I presented three times on two JSF topics. The conference was overall a great success in my opinion - while not the most highly attended conference at which I&amp;rsquo;ve presented, those that attended were highly engaged and happy to have such direct access to the speakers.
Indeed this was one of my preferred aspects to JAX conf.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seam Faces @JAXConf/JSF Summit</title>
      <link>bleathem.github.io/bleathem.ca/blog/seam-faces-jaxconf/jsf-summit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>bleathem.github.io/bleathem.ca/blog/seam-faces-jaxconf/jsf-summit/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since my last post, as I&amp;rsquo;ve gone through a significant career change. I am now working for Red Hat, as a core developer on the RichFaces project. I am also representing Red hat on the JSR-344: JSF 2.2 Expert Group, and will continue in my role as Seam Faces module lead.
As such, I&amp;rsquo;ll be presenting at JAXConf/JSF Summit on the topic of Seam Faces. I really like this presentation, as I not only go into the features provided by Seam Faces, but I show how some of those features are implemented taking advantage of the platform extension points built into CDI and JSF.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>