<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>RF42 on Experiences of a developer</title>
    <link>http://www.bleathem.ca/tags/rf42/</link>
    <description>Recent content in RF42 on Experiences of a developer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.bleathem.ca/tags/rf42/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>RichFaces 4.2.3.Final Release Announcement</title>
      <link>http://www.bleathem.ca/blog/richfaces-4.2.3.final-release-announcement/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.bleathem.ca/blog/richfaces-4.2.3.final-release-announcement/</guid>
      <description>RichFaces   RichFaces 4.2.3.Final has been released. This Final release is a re-tag of the 4.2.3.CR1 release as no blocking issues were found by either our QE team, nor by the community.
The RichFaces 4.2.3.Final release is purely a bug-fix release, with a focus on compatibility between RichFaces and the JBoss Portlet Bridge. I&amp;rsquo;ll refer you to the RichFaces 4.2.3.CR1 release blog for details of the release, with a special highlight paid to the contributions from the JBoss Portal Bridge team, and contributions from community members.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RichFaces 4.2.3.CR1 Release Announcement</title>
      <link>http://www.bleathem.ca/blog/richfaces-4.2.3.cr1-release-announcement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.bleathem.ca/blog/richfaces-4.2.3.cr1-release-announcement/</guid>
      <description>RichFaces   I am happy to announce that the first candidate release of RichFaces 4.2.3 (4.2.3.CR1) is now available. This is purely a bug-fix release, with a focus on compatibility between RichFaces and the JBoss Portlet Bridge.
div(alert alert-info). To try out this release: You can download the distribution directly, or for maven users, increment the RichFaces version in your pom.xml to 4.2.3.CR1. For more information on setting up a RichFaces 4 application, refer to ourgetting started guide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RichFaces 4.2.2.Final Release Announcement</title>
      <link>http://www.bleathem.ca/blog/richfaces-4.2.2.final-release-announcement/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.bleathem.ca/blog/richfaces-4.2.2.final-release-announcement/</guid>
      <description>RichFaces4.2.2.Final is available, the second RichFaces 4.2 micro release. This release was originally intended to focus on changes required to better align with the upcoming JBoss AS 7.1.2 release. However we had some community members step forward with some fixes, and those contributions ended up turning this release into a reasonable bug fix release!
I would like to give a big shout out to Luca Nardelli, Adrian Gonzalez, and Jason Porter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RichFaces 4.2.1.Final Release Announcement</title>
      <link>http://www.bleathem.ca/blog/richfaces-4.2.1.final-release-announcement/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.bleathem.ca/blog/richfaces-4.2.1.final-release-announcement/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ve released RichFaces4.2.1.Final - the first micro release for the 4.2 release train. Since the CR1 release we&amp;rsquo;ve primarily addressed bugs with the Richfaces showcase and the RichFaces archetypes. CR1 itself focused on bug fixes and stability improvements throughout the framework.
To try out this release, you can download the distribution directly, or for maven users, increment the RichFaces version in your pom.xml to 4.2.1.Final. For more information on setting up a RichFaces 4 application, refer to our getting started guide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RichFaces 4.2.1.CR1 Release Announcement</title>
      <link>http://www.bleathem.ca/blog/richfaces-4.2.1.cr1-release-announcement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.bleathem.ca/blog/richfaces-4.2.1.cr1-release-announcement/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ve released RichFaces 4.2.1.CR1 - the first candidate release for the first 4.2 micro release. This release comes with initial support for rapid component development with the CDK and jRebel, and a new archetype demonstrating (among other things) a mobile RichFaces application,. For the most part however, this release focuses on bug-fixes and stability of the components and framework.
To try out this release, you can download the distributiondirectly, or for maven users, increment the RichFaces version in your pom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RichFaces 4.2.0.Final Release Announcement</title>
      <link>http://www.bleathem.ca/blog/richfaces-4.2.0.final-release-announcement/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.bleathem.ca/blog/richfaces-4.2.0.final-release-announcement/</guid>
      <description>Richfaces 4.2.0.Final is now available for download! A quick follow on to our 4.1 release, Richfaces 4.2 delivers some “missing” components migrated from RichFaces 3, and provides usability and API improvements for resource loading optimizations and the push API. Documentation was a huge effort for this release; we are delivering an updated and complete VDL taglib doc, along with our more well established Developer Guide, and Components Reference.
To try out this release, you can download the distribution directly, or for maven users, increment the RichFaces version in your pom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RichFaces 4.2.0.CR1 Release Announcement</title>
      <link>http://www.bleathem.ca/blog/richfaces-4.2.0.cr1-release-announcement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.bleathem.ca/blog/richfaces-4.2.0.cr1-release-announcement/</guid>
      <description>I’m excited to announce the availability of RichFaces 4.2.0.CR1, our release candidate for RichFaces 4.2.0. Hot on the heels of the RichFaces 4.1 release, Richfaces 4.2 delivers some &amp;ldquo;missing&amp;rdquo; components migrated from RichFaces 3, and offers usability and API improvements for those looking to take advantage of our resource loading optimizations, and push API. Not to forget a significant number of bug fixes, and overall usability improvements.
To try out this release, you can download the distribution directly, or for maven users, increment the RichFaces version in your pom.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>